Thomas Mann Collection, 1881-1971: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 7: Photographs and Pictures, 1881-1960; 2 boxes (1 partial)
  - Julia Mann (née daSilva-Bruhns) (Mann's mother), 1 photograph, Lübeck, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Katja Mann, 9 photographs, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Monika Mann (Thomas Mann's daughter), 1 photograph, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Caroline Newton with Thomas Mann, 8 photographs (some duplicates), 1956 October; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Caroline Newton, 21 photographs (some duplicates), Commemoration, Bryn Mawr, 1956 October; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Buddenbrook House, 1 photograph, Lübeck, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Herzogpark House, 2 photographs, Munich, 1914; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Kilchberg House, 2 photographs, Switzerland, 1930s; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Thomas Mann, studio, and desk, 16 photographs (some duplicates), Kilchberg, Switzerland, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Princeton House, 65 Stockton Street, 1 photograph, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Jamestown, R. I. Cottage (cottage of Caroline Newton), 1 photograph (see also Box 12), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Thomas Mann Archive, 2 photographs, Zurich, Switzerland, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Thomas Mann grave, 10 photographs, 2 slides, Kilchberg, Switzerland, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Church near grave, 4 photographs, Kilchberg, Switzerland, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Bust and Death Mask, 3 photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - 1 caricature of Thomas Mann by Jack Rosen, signed by artist and subject; 1 etching of Thomas Mann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Portrait of Thomas Mann by Rudolf V. Ripper (watercolor), 1 photograph, 1940; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Portrait drawing by J. J. Muller, Princeton, 17.XII., 1938; 1 folder (Folder 33a)
  - Negatives, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Thomas Mann, 6 photographs, 1906-1955; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Thomas Mann by Edward Steichen, 2 (original) photographs, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Thomas Mann by "Mopp," original etching, 1930; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Katja Mann, 1 photograph, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Michael Mann (1919-1977) with his wife (Gret) and Caroline Newton, 3 photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Early family photographs, 2 photographs, 1906-1915; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Thomas Mann with grandson Frido, 1 photograph, 1942; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - "Buddenbrook" House, 1 photograph, Lübeck, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Jamestown, R. I. Cottage (cottage of Caroline Newton), 1 photograph, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Thomas Mann, 1 photograph (rolled), (?), 1955; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Plaque, 65 Stockton Street, Princeton, N. J., 1 photograph (rolled), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Series 8: Printed Matter by Thomas Mann, 1930 October 17-1970; portions of 2 boxes
  Consists of printed matter by Thomas Mann, including addresses, essays, and published correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 3 addresses by Thomas Mann, 1939-1943 (negatives), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - "Ansprache in Geothejahr," 21 pp., 1949; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - "Bruder Hitler," essay in Das neue Tagebuch, 1939 March 25; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - "Ein Appell an die Vernunft," Deutsche Ansprache, Berlin, 1930 October 17 (2 copies, boxed), 1 folder (Folder 38)
  - "Jaacobs Hochzeit" (boxed) in "Corona," Oldenburg Verlag, 1931-1932, with inscription to Hedwig Fischer, 12/16/31, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - "Lob der Verganglichkeit," 4 pp, 1952, with inscription to Caroline Newton, 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - "Versuch uber Schiller," 104 pp., 1955, with inscription to Caroline Newton, 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - "Versuch uber Tschechow," in Die Neue Rundschau, 22 pp., 1956; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - "Walsungenblut," 2 pp. Original ending of story, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Published correspondence between Thomas Mann and Erich V. Kahler (1938-1955), 67 pp., 1970; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Published correspondence between Thomas Mann and the Philosophy faculty of Bonn (1936-1937), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Published correspondence between Thomas Mann and Hans Reisiger (1933-1955), 43 pp., 1938; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Series 9: Printed Matter about Thomas Mann, 1928-1963 April 27; 3 boxes (2 partial)
  Consists of printed matter about Thomas Mann, including announcements, articles, clippings, essays, interviews, and reviews.
  - Announcement of new editions, films, dealers lists, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Thomas Mann Archive, Zurich. 2 announcements, 1958; 1 guide, 1963; and 3 news clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Thomas Mann Issue of Du, 1955 June, for Mann's 80th birthday, 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous writings (clippings) regarding Thomas Mann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous writings (articles and photocopies) regarding Thomas Mann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Photographs-printed material, announcements, clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Lowe-Porter, H. T. (1877-1963), Thomas Mann translator. Obituary, N. Y. Times, 1963 April 27 (clipping), 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Mann, Klaus (1906-1949). Articles by and about K. Mann (clippings and periodicals), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Reviews ( Kritiken), 1928, German scrapbook, 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, mounted (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, mounted (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, mounted (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Articles, essays, interviews by Thomas Mann, clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Articles about Thomas Mann, newspaper clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Book reviews of Thomas Mann works, newspaper clippings (in German and in English), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Thomas Mann, 80th birthday, 1955, newspaper clippings, 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Thomas Mann, death, 1955, newspaper clippings (in German and in English), 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Series 10: Recordings, 1942; 1 folder
  Consists of Joseph and His Brothers, Thomas Mann reads selections from his work, in German and in English, recorded at Columbia University as well as 5 phonograph recordings.
  - Joseph and His Brothers, Thomas Mann reads selections from his work, in German and in English, recorded at Columbia University, 1942; 1 box 5 phonograph recordings
- 32101037090428 (Box 1)
- 32101037090436 (Box 2)
- 32101037090444 (Box 3)
- 32101037090451 (Box 4)
- 32101037090469 (Box 5)
- 32101037090477 (Box 6)
- 32101037090485 (Box 7)
- 32101037090493 (Box 8)
- 32101037090535 (Box 12)
- 32101037090501 (Box 9)
- 32101037090519 (Box 10)
- 32101037090527 (Box 11)
- 32101080519430 (Box 13)